Stephen E. Malawista papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Research materials, Series XI
  - Laboratory notebooks and binders (Restricted), Subseries 2
    - Notebooks begun 1962-1970
      - R.H. Gifford, Vol. I, Experiments1-99, ca. 1968 (Box 75, Folder 9)
        of the series are in the next section, Notebooks begun, 1971-1975.
      - R.H. Gifford, Vol. II, Experiments 100-175, 1968 November-1969 August (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - R.H. Gifford, Vol. III, Experiments 176-256, 1969 August-1970 February (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - R.H. Gifford, Vol. IV, Experiments 257-368, 1970 February-1970 October (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - R.H. Gifford, Vol. V, Experiments 369-658, 1970 October-1973 July (Box 75, Folder 13)
        See additional R.H. Gifford notebook with numbered experiments in the next section, Notebooks begun 1971-1975.
      - Carol C. Teitz, bone marrow tests, 1970 June-1970 July (Box 75, Folder 14)
        Patient names are prominent. Restricted.
      - M.L.B., 1970 October-1971 July (Box 75, Folder 15)
        Some entries in Malawista's handwriting.
    - Notebooks begun 1971-1975
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XIII, Frog Skins, Book 2, 1971 February-1972 May (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XIV, Cyto[chalasin] Bs, Cyclic AMPs, 1971 March-June (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XV, General, 1971 December-1973 March (Box 75, Folder 18)
        "Cont. from Book XI"
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XVI, Mark Bitensky, 1972 April-1977 May (Box 75, Folder 19)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XVII, General, 1975 May-1976 July (Box 76, Folder 1)
        "Acid P + Lectins" written on front cover.
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XVIII, 1975 September-1977 August (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - N. Cannarozzi, M.D., "Adventures in Phagocytosis measured by I-HSA", 1971 September-1972 May (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - "I-131 Exp. Cont. (Dr. C[annarozzi]", 1972 May- 1974 February (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - R.H.G. [Robert H. Gifford] and SBC, "The New Era", 1972 September-November (Box 76, Folder 5)
        Only a few pages of the notebook were used. Contains patient names.
      - R. H. Gifford, Vol. VI, Experiments 659-733, 1973 July-1979 November (Box 76, Folder 6)
        Also contains entries on the "New Born Study."
      - Tissue culture, Book I, 1973 November-1975 July (Box 76, Folder 7)
        Experiments on sera from rats and mice.
      - Mark Schwartz, "Phagocytosis, Urate", 1974 September-1975 July (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - Allen Steere,1975 July-1975 November (Box 76, Folder 9)
        Notebook is about procedures such as "Harvesting White Cells." Most of the volume is blank.
      - U-12 Cont. Book II, 1975 July-1976 March (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - Mary Jean Ahern, M.D., data on transplant patients, 1975 July-1976 June (Box 76, Folder 11)
        Contains patient names.
    - Notebooks begun 1976-1980
      - Tissue Culture, Book III, 1976 February-1978 February (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - "U-12 Continue, Book III", 1976 March-1978 June (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - "RNA, DNA, Cryoglobulins", 1976 August (Box 76, Folder 14)
        Most of the volume is blank.
      - Cyclic AMP I, 1977 May-1978 July (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - C[yclic] AMP II, 1978 July-1981 March (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - "U-12 Cont. IV", 1978 June-1985 July (Box 76, Folder 17)
      - S.E. Malawista, Paris, 1978 September-1980 April (Box 76, Folder 18)
        Mostly in Malawista's handwriting.
      - "Con A", 1979 May-June (Box 77, Folder 1)
        Most of volume is blank.
      - Mary Nakamura, 1980-1984 (Box 77, Folder 2)
        Contains patient names and dates of birth. Restricted.
      - Fragments I, 1980 September-1981 March (Box 77, Folder 3)
        Fragments in the cytoplasm of a cell.
    - Notebooks begun 1981-1985
      - Fragments II, 1881 March-1982 May (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - "Cyclic-AMP" III, 1981 May-1983 February (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - "Frag III", 1982 May-1983 February (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - "Frag IV", 1983 February-1983 August (Box 77, Folder 7)
      - "Frag V", 1983 August-1984 March (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - Borrelia, !983 October-December (Box 77, Folder 9)
        Borrelia burgdorferi is the bacterial cause of Lyme disease. Experiments are preceded by a page of directions, "Counting Treponemes," by Robert Grodzicki, September 16, 1982.
      - "Frag VI", 1984 February-1984 August (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - "Fragments Book VII", 1984 September-1985 April (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - "Frag Book VIII", 1985 April-1986 January (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Notebooks begun 1986-1995
      - S.E. Malawista, Paris, 1989 January-September, 1991 February (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Lin Lin Fu, Tests of ticks for Lyme disease, 1993 April-1995 September (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - Tests of ticks for Lye disease, 1993-1996 (Box 77, Folder 15)
        Contains photographs related to PCR tests. Only a few pages of the notebook were used.
      - Lin Lin Fu, Tests of ticks for Lyme disease, 1995 October-1998 April (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Ringed binder notebooks
      - S.E. Malawista, Research, Paris, 1972 December-1973 July (Box 78, Folder 1)
        Notebook is mainly in Malawista's handwriting.
      - Lyme Arthritis: "Tot[al] Prot[ein] and Ig [Immunoglobulin] M, A, & G graphs", 1977 May-1981 January (Box 78, Folder 2)
        Contains patient names. Includes printed brochures on some of the products used for testing.
      - Deborah Dyett, Book I, 1983 December-1985 April (Box 78, Folder 3)
        Includes "donor" names. Topics include chemotaxis and capping.
      - Deborah Dyett, Book II, 1984 July-1985 July (Box 78, Folder 4)
        Topics include superoxides, calcium, actin polymerization, and OSM. Contains "donor" names. There is a multi-page readout of data and graphs from a Beckman DU-40 Spectrophotometer.
      - Defensins, 1986 June-July (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Contains glass plates.
      - "Aggregation", 1986 August-November (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Mostly graphs. Contains "donor" names.
      - S.E. Malawista, Research, Paris, 1987 July-1988 October (Box 78, Folder 7)
        Includes research photographs and X-ray plates.
      - Research on PBMC, PMN, PML, etc., 2008-2009 (Box 78, Folder 8)
        Binder labeled "Dr. Malawista 3" containing typed experiments and computer-generated colored charts.
  - Videocassettes, 1983-1987; Subseries 3 (Box 79)
    11 large videocassettes (SONY KCA-60K), one somewhat smaller videocassette (JVC E-30), and a notebook. The notebook contains a description of the first seven tapes. They contain images of phagocytes, fragments, cytokineplasts (CKP), etc.
  - Research notes and correspondence, Subseries 4
    This section contains loose research notes and photographs, sometimes with accompanying correspondence.
    - Miscellaneous experiment: joint fluid pH, 1962 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Research on colchicine, 1963-1964 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous experiment: Phagocytosis, 1964- (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Colchicine-melanocytes, key experiments, 1964-1965 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous experiment: chloroquine sarcoid, 1965- (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous experiment: colchicine-histamine, 1965- (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous experiment: melanocyte D 2O frog skin, 1965- (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous experiment: melanocyte-trypson, 1965- (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, 1965 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, 1965 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, 1966-1967 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Frog Skins (colchicine), 1967- (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Vinblastine, 1967- (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Photographs, colchicine - staph - guinea pigs, 1968, February (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Research with Hidemi Sato, 1969 (Box 80, Folder 15)
      Hidemi Sato was at the Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, with Malawista. At this time Sato was in the Department of Biology, University of Pennsylvania. Malawista and Sato collaborated on several papers.
    - Pisaster orchraceous (isolated spindle), Friday Harbor, 1969- (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Research with Mary C. Weiss on karyology, 1972-1973 (Box 80, Folder 17)
      Copy of a notebook labeled in Malawista's hand "Karyologie/ Malawista & Weiss/ 1972-73." Weiss was at the Centre de Genetique Moleculaire, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, Paris.
    - Research on the S family (Restricted), 1978, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Research with Roger Sloboda, 1978-1979, 1985 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      Malawista and Sloboda collaborated on griseofulvin. Sloboda was in the Department of Biological Sciences, Dartmouth College.
    - Research and correspondence with Anne Chevance and others in Paris, 1981-1983 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Copy of a notebook listing photos taken, Paris, 1983 October-November (Box 81, Folder 3)
      In Malawista's hand.
    - Cytokineplasts phagocytosis: 1 degree data, 1986- (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - PNAS paper data, cytokineplasts, 1986- (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Cryopreservable cytoplasts, 1986-1988 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      Research notes, including a draft abstract for the 1988 meeting of Association of American Physicians. See Articles 93, Box 28, Folder 1.
    - Research on O cytoplasts, fresh or frozen/thawed, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Research and correspondence with Anne Chevance, 1990-1991 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Research with Anne Chevance on tick saliva, 1996-1999 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Research with Anne Chevance on urate crystals, 1997-1999 (Box 81, Folder 10)
      Labeled photographs that Chevance sent to Malawista.
    - Research with Anne Chevance, 2003-2004 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Research with Charles Serhan and Anne Chevance on EDTA, etc., 2003-2004 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Research with Anne Chevance on hemozoin, 2006 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Research with Anne Chevance and others, Paris, 2007-2009 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Research with Charles Serhan on MSU incubations, etc., 2009 (Box 81, Folder 15)
- Oversize, 1979-2013; Series XII
  - Photographs, circa 1979-2013 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Photograph, Harvard Class of 1954 - 25th Reunion, 1979, June 3 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Poster, Neutrophils and Inflammation Symposium, 2004, April 23 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Poster, From There to Here: a Half Century in Biomedicine, Leadership in Biomedicine Lecture Series, 2010, October 20 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Poster, A Newspaper Survey of the Discovery of Lyme Disease, 1976-1978, 13th International Conference on Lyme Borreliosis and Other Tick-Borne Diseases, 2013 (Box 82, Folder 5)